Chris Vaillancourt

ABOUT ME

Data Visualization & Cartography

Since 2014

Empathetic and agile practitioner of data analysis and visualization with 5 years of relevant experience. Specialist in front-end development, information design, and geospatial visualization. Adept to work in academic, research and private sector environments.

EXPERIENCE

Data Visualization Engineer

Feb 2019 - Present | Esri

- Develop responsive web applications using Esri's JavaScript API, Leaflet, and D3
- ② Lead technical development for media strategy team
- Manage engagement strategy, resulting in 65% increase in user engagement
- Advise clients on data analysis, visualization, and development best practices
- O Craft and lead training sessions on Esri technology

Mapping Specialist

Nov 2016 - Feb 2019 | Esri

- Designed and developed custom map visualizations for commercial clients
- Increased performance of data-driven applications by an average of 15%
- Provided technical product support to teams across marketing and communication channels
- Revamped software training curriculum for media clients

Solution Engineer Internship

May 2016 – Aug 2016 | Esri

- Crafted map visualization products for conferences and trade shows
- Created and presented technical demonstrations to small business customers
- Constructed and delivered geographic databases for research and development

Advanced GIS Internship

June 2015 - May 2016 | START

- Produced maps and technical reports on global terrorism methods, food insecurity, and piracy
- Developed global geospatial finance database through open-source research
- ⊙ Compiled and researched a global, multimodal transportation network database
- Led technical presentations for university researchers

EDUCATION

University of Maryland, College Park

2012 - 2016 | Bachelor of Science

Major: Geographic Information Science and Cartography

Minors: Business & Philosophy

GPA: 3.75

Academic Accomplishments:

Undergraduate Research Symposium Award - First Place

Dean's List - 6 of 8 semesters Phi Beta Kappa Honor Society

SKILLS

Web & Data Visualization

JavaScript (ES6+)		CSS	ArcGIS API for JavaScript			
D3.js	Leaflet	Svelte	React Git	GitHub		
Rollup	llup Parcel Respo		nsive Layout and Design			
Photoshop Illustrator						

Geospatial

AcrGIS Pro	ArcMap		ArcGIS Online	
Mapshaper CLI		QGIS	GDAL	

CONTACT

- © chrisvaillancourt.github.io
- O twitter.com/CV_Cartography
- ☐ chris.d.vaillancourt@gmail.com
- **%** (619) 630 9056
- San Diego, CA